Solidarity Committee of the Capital District; Records apap042
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Photographs, 1988-1993; 4; 0.2 cubic ft.
  - Grape Boycott & United Farm Workers, 1988-1992; 4.4 (Box 1 (4-Photographs), Folder 4)
    - March on Washington
      Union banners were in place as nearly 100,000 people joined in a 25th anniversary renewal of the 1963 March on Washington that demanded and achieved passage of the Civil Rights Act. The dream of which Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. spoke is still alive the rally testified. (36-3-88).
  - Greyhound Strike, 1990-1991; 4.5 (Box 1 (4-Photographs), Folder 5)
    - Teamsters Rally Greyhound Strikers
      Teamsters President, William J. McCarthy leads ITB members in a St. Louis march supporting Amalgamated Transit Workers, on strike against Greyhound bus lines for the past three months. Some 325 delegates to the IBT central states conference joined in the demonstration. (11-1-90).
    - Taking a Walk
      Striking members of the Amalgamated Transit Union march to Washington's Union Station for a rally in their continuing efforts to win a fail settlement at Greyhound bus lines. March leaders included ATU President James LaSala and civil rights leaders Jesse Jackson and Rosa Parks. The ATU struck Greyhound on March 2. (13-1-90).
    - Riding Out the Struggle
      Pledges of labor solidarity with striking members of the Amalgamated Transit Union are made by AFL-CIO President Lane Kirkland at the Greyhound bus terminal in Louisville, KY. Helping man the picket line were federation Vice Presidents William Bywater and Richard Trumka, as well as Kentucky AFL-CIO president Robert Curtis and Executive Secretary-Treasurer Ronald Cyrus. The ATU has been on strike against Greyhound since March 2. (21-2-90).
    - Support for Greyhound Strikers
      Members of Amalgamated Transit Union Local 1600 in New Orleans were buoyed by a show of solidarity from delegates to the Letter Carriers' convention. NALC President Vincent Sombrotto, center, leads members in picketing outside the Greyhound terminal. (18-3-90).
    - On ATU's Picket Line
      This youngster joins in a rally at the Washington, DC Greyhound terminal where 150 trade unionists show their support for the 9,300 Amalgamated Transit Union members who have been on strike against Greyhound Lines Inc., since last March 2. Rallies were held in Atlanta, New York, Detroit, Dallas, Cincinnati, and Portland, Ore., where Brenda Bowman was a guest speaker. Bowman is the daughter of Bob Waterhouse, a striker who was killed by a scab-driven bus in Redding, Calif. (18-4-90).
    - In Memory of Robert Waterhouse, 1990 March
      Flowers mark the spot where ATU member Robert Waterhouse was killed by a scab Greyhound driver in Redding, Calif. (6-2-90).
    - ATU Strike Stalls Greyhound Runs, 1990 March
      Union supports rally striking members of the Amalgamated Transit Union in Washington as the nation-wide walkout against Greyhound Lines rolled into its third week. A scab bus driver ran into a police cruiser during the demonstration commemorating the death of a striking driver. (6-1-90).
    - Milwaukee Greyhound Rally, 1991 January
      Bruce Colburn, President of Amalgamated Transit Union Local 98 and head of the Milwaukee AFL-CIO's solidarity committee, leads the call for justice for Greyhound strikers at a rally outside Milwaukee's federal building where the National Labor Relations Board was conducting a hearing on an unfair labor practice complaint against Greyhound. (2-4-91).
  - Laundry Workers Strike, 1984-1985 (Box 1 (4-Photographs), Folder 6)
    Unidentified and Undated.
    Two photos, one of a woman and the other of a woman, horse and little girl, were found with the files on the Laundry Workers Strike in Stillwater, 1984-85. The photos are neither labeled nor dated. There are negatives included.
  - Legislative Photos, Undated (Box 1 (4-Photographs), Folder 7)
    Three black and white photos: first is Senator Robert C. Byrd, second is AFL-CIO Secretary-Treasurer Thomas R. Donahue speaking to the Senate Labor & Human Resources Committee, and the third is Rep. John Conyers, Jr. meeting with union officials about high unemployment issues.
  - Minimum Wage (Box 1 (4-Photographs), Folder 8)
    Minimum Wage Call-Up.
    Offices of House Education & Labor Committee Chairman Augustus F. Hawkins (D-Calif.) is the Capitol Hill link of an AFL-CIO conference call to spur a grassroots lobbying effort in support of an effective minimum wage bill. Hawkins, center, is the bill's sponsor. Rep. Pat Williams (D-Mont.) is on the phone to union leaders in 14 key southern states. AFL-CIO Legislative Director Robert M. McGlotten, left, coordinated the congressional calls. Other AFL-CIO departments participated from the federation's headquarters. (24-4-88).
  - General, 4.9 (Box 1 (4-Photographs), Folder 9)
    - Black & White Photo, unlabeled, Undated
      Photo depicts five men walking through industrial setting.
    - Editorial Cartoon, Undated
      Black and white cartoon originating from AFL-CIO News; construction worker with "Senate upholds wage protections" sign.
    - Community Event
      There are six color photos of a community fair of some kind outside a church. There is no indication of who the sponsors are or where the fair is being held.
    - Fired up by Colt, 1987 April 16
      A thousand trade unionists rally outside Colt Industries headquarters in New York in support of 1,100 locked out autoworkers. Members of UAW Local 376 in Hartford, CT were without a contract for 10 months prior to walking out. The state declared the impasse a lockout in August when the company refused to bargain. The National Labor Relations Board issued a complaint against Colt for its refusal to bargain.
    - Demonstration
      There are eight photos of a demonstration. However, there is no indication of the date, place, or people in the photos.
      International Longshoreman, Local 333 United Marine Division Strike.
      Black and white photo of two men holding placards indicating their support for the union and the strike. There is no indication of the date or place of the photograph or the identification of the men in the picture.
    - Ravenswood Battle Goes On
      A huge marionette of legendary union organizer Mary Harris "Mother" Jones is greeted with applause by Ravenswood Aluminum Corp. stakeholders in Charleston, WV. The Steelworkers called the January 22 meeting to challenge the company's demeaning attitude toward workers and the community. RAC "permanently replaces 1,700 USWA members with scabs in November 1990". (March, 1 1992).
    - Solidarity Day, 1991 August 31
      Included are 12 color photos of the Solidarity Day and rally in Washington, D.C. that drew more than 325,000 union members and their allies. The photos consist primarily of crowd/group shots. Most groups had on special t-shirts and or carried signs. (See the September 9 issue of the AFL-CIO News for details.).
    - Teamsters Elect Ron Carey
      At a Washington press conference, Ron Carey claims victory in a three-way race for the presidency of the Teamsters. Carey, 54, was president of IBT Local 804 in Queens, NY and drew 48.5% of the membership vote; R.V. Durham 33.2%; and Walter Shea 18.2%. Durham filed a protest with federal elections officers who conducted the membership election. January 2, 1992.
    - Unlabeled, Undated
      There are several photographs that are neither labeled nor dated.
      The black and white photo is coded 21-1-91 and it appears to be some kind of hearing or testimony, with three men sitting at a table with microphones.
      Another photo is color and appears to be a planning and or business meeting.(To the far left with her back to the photo is Pat Beetle(?) and to the far left is John Funicello.).
  - NAFTA and US-Mexico Free Trade, 4.10 (Box 1 (4-Photographs), Folder 10)
    - He Died for 45 Cents an Hour, April 29, Undated
      Fighting back tears, Elizabeth Macias describes at Senate hearings how her 16-year-old son was killed at a Ford Motor Co. glass plant in Juarez, Mexico, during his first week on the job. The Ford maquiladora was paying him 45 cents an hour as a production worker when he was hacked to death in an underground waste grinder. Attorney Gustavo de la Rosa Hickerson and interpreter Alicia Edwards at the US-Mexico trade policy hearings accompany Mrs. Macias. (9-1-91).
    - NAFTA Job Drain
      This ad by a US broker was displayed during Senate hearings on the North American Free Trade Agreement showing how runaway American manufacturers can exploit Mexican workers at poverty pay levels of less than $1 an hour. (8-2-93).
    - Shame of the Maquiladoras
      Struggling to make ends meet with poverty-level wages, workers at Mexico's maquiladora plants are forced to live in shantytowns on polluted streams. But President Bush continues to press for the North American Free Trade Agreement that woefully lacks worker rights and environmental safeguards. (3-3-91).
    - Job-Gutting Trade Pact, October 12, Undated
      With their jobs on the line, union members rally in San Antonio to protest the dire impact the US-Mexico-Canada trade accord will have on their livelihoods. The demonstration came with the ceremonial initialing of NAFTA by President Bush, Mexican President Carlos Salinas and Canadian Prime Minister Brian Mulroney. (21-1-92).
    - US-Mexico Trade
      More American jobs will be wiped out under President Bush's proposed free trade agreement with Mexico, Electronic Workers President William H. Bywater tells reporters as IUE members picket outside the Commerce Department. The Bush administration is seeking renewal of 'fast track' authority, which would bar amendments and limit discussion on the trade proposal. (7-4-91). (Editors: See April 1, 1991, issue of AFL-CIO News for details.).
  - Solidarity Day, 1991 August 31 (Box 1 (4-Photographs), Folder 11)
    Included are 12 color photos of the Solidarity Day march and rally in Washington, DC that drew more than 325,000 union members and their allies. The photos consist primarily of crowd/group shots. Most groups had on special t-shirts and or carried signs. (See the September 9 issue of the AFL-CIO News for details.).
  - Teamsters Local 72 & NYS Thruway Authority, Undated (Box 1 (4-Photographs), Folder 12)
    Includes three unlabeled, undated photos (2 black and white, 1 color) of a demonstration near the NYS Thruway Authority building in Albany. The two black and white photos show SCCD chairman John Funiciello and another subject shaking hands and conversing. The color photo shows SCCD member Doug Bullock with a Solidarity banner.
- Series 5: Videotapes, 1994-1997, Undated; 11 items
  The collection includes eleven VHS format videocassettes. The programs include local issues and news and documentaries concerning many of the social activism and social justice issues that the Solidarity Committee has tackled over the years. Several of the programs are undated.
  Oversize Materials, 2 cubic ft., Arranged by subject.
  This part of the collection contains materials that are larger than the standard legal size. The materials are primarily posters, newsletters, and maps. Each folder in the oversized boxes refers to a box and folder number with the Administrative Files or Subject Files series.
  (* On the same videotape).
  AFSCME and Greyhound, Broadcast NY, VHS.
  The Burning Season, VHS.
  *Deadly Deception: GE, Nuclear Weapons and Our Environment, 29 minutes, VHS.
  Higher Education and Economy, VHS.
  *Independent Focus, 2 hours, VHS.
  L.P. Footage, November 6, 1997, VHS.
  Our Forgotten War, El Salvador, VHS.
  Save Us All Sampler, GESU, 1996, VHS.
  *Short Documentary Films, VHS.
  Solidarity News, VHS.
  Workfare Hearing Jobs with Justice and Solidarity Committee, March 11, 1997, VHS.
  Workers' Rights Board Hearing re: Workfare & March 19th Coalition March 11, 1997.
- Oversize Materials, 6
  - Financial Records, Log Sheets, 1984 (Box 1 (6-Oversize Materials), Folder 1)
  - Flyers and Pamphlets, Labor History Month Poster and Flyer of Exhibits and Events, 1999 (Box 1 (6-Oversize Materials), Folder 2)
  - AFL-CLO, Union Label Poster, 2000 (Box 1 (6-Oversize Materials), Folder 3)
  - American Postal Workers Union-Miscellaneous-Posters (Box 1 (6-Oversize Materials), Folder 4)
    (Series 3, Box 4, Folder 2).
  - American Postal Workers Union, Newsletters, Postal Press, 1991-1993 (Box 1 (6-Oversize Materials), Folder 5)
    (Series 3, Box 4 Folder 3).
  - American Postal Workers Union-Newsletters, The American Postal Worker, 1997-1999 (Box 1 (6-Oversize Materials), Folder 6)
  - American Postal Workers Union, Newsletters, News Service, 1989-1992 (Box 1 (6-Oversize Materials), Folder 7)
  - Memorabilia, Undated (Box 1 (6-Oversize Materials), Folder 8)
  - American Postal Workers Union, Newsletters, News Service, 1989-1992 (Box 2 (6-Oversize Materials), Folder 1)
  - Environment, Draft Study for a Hudson Valley Greenway, 1990 (Box 2 (6-Oversize Materials), Folder 2)
    Maps: Hudson River Valley Greenway Trails, Rails, Roads and Public Lands; Greenway Study Area by County, City, Town, and Village (Series 3, Box 8, Folder 7).
  - Environment, Greenpeace, Newsletters, 1990-1993 (Box 2 (6-Oversize Materials), Folder 3)
  - Environment, Poster Map of New York State funded Dumps, 1995 (Box 2 (6-Oversize Materials), Folder 4)
  - Greyhound, Amalgamated Transit Workers Union, Local 1202, Poster, 1990 (Box 2 (6-Oversize Materials), Folder 5)
  - Hormel, United Food and Commercial Workers (Box 2 (6-Oversize Materials), Folder 6)
    New York Times Feature, June 14, 1987; Washington Post Feature, November 3, 1987 (Series 3, Box 12, Folder 9).
  - Privatization, Wanted Poster of Anthony M. Frank, Postmaster General, Privatization, 1989-1992 (Box 2 (6-Oversize Materials), Folder 7)
  - Labor Day, Celebrations, 1999-2000 (Box 2 (6-Oversize Materials), Folder 8)
    Poster (Series 3, Box 17, Folder 1).
  - National Arts Program Poster: sponsored by Leonard E.B. Andrews Foundation, Pennsylvania, Undated (Box 2 (6-Oversize Materials), Folder 9)
  - New York State Assembly, Congressional Voting Record for Labor-related Bills, Undated (Box 2 (6-Oversize Materials), Folder 10)
    City of Schenectady City Council Resolution, 2000 Series 3, Box 22, Folder 8.
  - Tek Toothbrushes Poster: Brushworkers Local 20468, AFL-CIO, Undated (Box 2 (6-Oversize Materials), Folder 11)